Guide to the Office of Cultural Affairs Records, 1931-2002 (bulk 1958-2002)
Duke University. University Archives
Office of Cultural Affairs 1931-2002, bulk 1958-2002
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Office of Cultural Affairs
16 linear feet Extent: 16,000 Items
The Duke University Office of Cultural Affairs was created in 1969 as part of the Division of Student Affairs and existed until 1993, when, as part of a reorganization of the Division, it was superceded by the Office of University Life. The Office of Cultural Affairs Records, 1931-2002 (bulk 1958-2002), consist of budgets and financial reports; calendars; contracts; correspondence; meeting minutes; printed materials; black-and-white, color, and 35mm photographs; and videocassettes, audiocassettes, and digital audio tapes. Materials primarily span the years of the OCA's official existence, 1969-1993, but also contain earlier materials about its first director, Ella Fountain Pratt, and later records created by the Office of University Life. Arranged in five series: Subject Files, which provide a broad overview of the OCA's activities, including early correspondence between Duke University and the American Dance Festival, which moved to Duke in 1977; the Chamber Arts Society, a group that promoted chamber music performance in Durham and surrounding areas; the Duke Artists Series, a concert series that began in 1930 and came under the oversight of OCA upon its creation in 1969; the Summer Session, programming for which also became one of the OCA's primary responsibilities; and the Triangle Dance Guild, a group independent of Duke that coordinated with the OCA to promote dance performance on campus and in Durham and surrounding areas from 1976-1984.
UA.09.08.0002
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Office of Cultural Affairs Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer, 1971-2003.
Historical Note
The Duke University Office of Cultural Affairs was created in 1969 as part of the Division of Student Affairs and directed by Ella Fountain Pratt from its inception until 1984. Pratt was succeeded by Susan L. Cook, who served as Director until 1993, when the Office was superceded by the Office of University Life as part of a reorganization of the Division.
Collection Overview
The Office of Cultural Affairs Records, 1931-2002 (bulk 1958-2002), consist of budgets and financial reports, calendars, contracts, correspondence, meeting minutes, photographs, and printed materials that document the Office's administration and scheduling of concerts and other performing arts events, arts festivals, and certain performance venues and buildings on the campus of Duke University. The majority of these records span the years of the OCA's official existence, 1969-1993; but there are also older materials that stem from the earlier Duke career of the OCA's initial director, Ella Fountain Pratt, as well as later records created under the Office of University Life, which superceded the OCA in 1993. Audiovisual material in the collection include more than 500 black-and-white, color, and 35mm photographs; additionally, there are several videocassettes, audiocassettes, and digital audio tapes. The collection is arranged in five series beginning with the most general, Subject Files, followed in alphabetical order by four smaller and more specific series that document the history of various concert series or arts organizations.
The Subject Files are not only the largest series but also give the broadest overview of the OCA's activities. Several large folder groups exist within the series, including one that contains early correspondence and negotiations between Duke University and the American Dance Festival, which moved to Duke in 1977. The series also contains correspondence and other records that span Pratt's entire career at Duke, from the late 1950s through her retirement in 1984. The next four series document the history of various concert series or artistic groups that were either administrated by or collaborated with the OCA. The first and largest of these series is the Chamber Arts Society. Founded in 1945 to promote chamber music performance in Durham, this group eventually came under the aegis of Duke University and the Office of Cultural Affairs in 1975. Although files here tell a little of that early history, they primarily document some fifteen years of concerts on campus from the mid-1980s through 2002. Following this are the records of the Duke Artists Series, a concert series that began in 1930. When the OCA was created in 1969, management and oversight of the Duke Artists Series was made one of its primary responsibilities. The files here mainly document several seasons of concerts in the late 1980s and late 1990s. Much like the Duke Artists Series, cultural programming for the University's Summer Session Series also became a primary responsibility of the OCA upon its creation. This series covers more than forty years of summer session history, including programming that continued under the Office of University Life. The final series contains the history of the Triangle Dance Guild. Independent of Duke, this group existed from 1976-1984 and coordinated with the OCA to promote dance performance on campus and in Durham and other local venues.
Subject Headings
Pratt, Ella Fountain; American Dance Festival -- History; Chamber Arts Society (Duke University); Duke Artists Series; Duke University -- Buildings; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University. Office of Cultural Affairs; Duke University. Office of University Life; Duke University. Summer Session; Triangle Dance Guild; Concerts -- North Carolina -- Durham; Festivals -- North Carolina -- Durham; Performing arts -- North Carolina -- Durham; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Slides (photographs); Audiocassettes; Digital audio tapes; Videocassettes
Detailed Description of Collection
- Subject Files, 1934-2000, (6 boxes)
  Materials relating to the administration and management of the Office of Cultural Affairs, including budgets, box office reports, correspondence, event and season calendars, and files about specific artists and performances. In addition to the wide variety of individual files, four larger folder groups in the series document the following subjects in greater detail: Ella Fountain Pratt's work on the exective board of the Association of College, University and Community Arts Administrators (ACUCAA); recruitment of the American Dance Festival (ADF) to Duke in the 1970s; history of the usage, maintenance, and physical improvements made to Page Auditorium; and records of the first fifteen years of the Mary Lou Williams Jazz Festival (1983-1998). In various files the series also contains information spanning most of the career of Ella Fountain Pratt at Duke University; more extensive material about her can be found in the Ella Fountain Pratt Papers. Visual materials in the series include blueprints of Page Auditorium, circa 1960, and approximately forty black-and-white photographs of various performers. Files are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  RESTRICTIONS: See the Access Restrictions section of this finding aid for description of written permissions required to use materials within twenty-five years from the origin of the material.
  [Restricted until 2025.]
  - Ad Hoc Commission on the Arts, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Commission on the Arts--report, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Symposium--"The Beauty of Black," 1969 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Davis L., 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - American Dance Festival (ADF), 1976-1978, (11 folders)
    Related materials: the Rubenstein Library serves as the public point-of-access for all collections held by the American Dance Festival Archives.
    - Box office reports, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
    - Duke commitments, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Fund, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
    - Fund raising, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Gala, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Inventory, 1977 (Box 1)
    - News clippings, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Proposal, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Tuition, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Visits, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - American Musical Theater Center, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Annual report, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Articles by Ella Fountain Pratt, undated (Box 1)
  - Arts at Duke, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Arts at Noon, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Arts Festival, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Les Arts Florissants, 1987 Nov. 20 (Box 1)
  - Arts in Duke Chapel, 1978-1986, (5 folders)
    - Alain, Marie-Claire, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Chancel Opera, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
    - Messiah, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
    - St. Matthew Passion, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Printed material, 1980-1986 (Box 1)
  - Arts in the Church Conference, 1979-1982, (6 folders) (Box 1)
    Correspondence, evaluations, finances, memoranda, and black-and-white photographs.
  - Association of African Students, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Association of College Unions, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - Association of College, University and Community Arts Administrators (ACUCAA), 1958-1979, (13 folders)
    - Annual conferences, 1960-1979, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Committee on the Arts, 1966-1969 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1974 (Box 1)
    - Duke profile survey, 1969-1979, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
    - Membership, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
    - Wingspread Conference, 1973-1977 (Box 1)
    - Workshop for Arts Administrators, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Workshop for Concert Managers, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Workshop for Performing Arts Admistrators, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Atlanta Contemporary Dance Company, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Attendance figures, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Bachauer, Gina, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
  - Berman, Lazar, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Bernstein's Mass, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Box office reports, 1973-1984, (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - British-American Festival, 1984--see "Raleigh's Dream" (Box 2)
  - Bryan University Center--dedication, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Bryan University Center--technical services, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Budget, 1970-1984, (8 folders) (Box 2)
  - Caecilien-Verein concert in Duke Chapel, 1980 July (Box 2)
  - Cameron Indoor Stadium--seating statistics, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Cantori di Assisi, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Chancellor's Advisory Committee on Instruction in the Arts, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Chuck Davis' African American Dance Ensemble, 1991 Mar 22 (Box 2)
  - "Civilisation" Film Series, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1982, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: letters to Ella Fountain Pratt upon her retirement, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Dalton, Harry, 1961-1977, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Devi, Ritha, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
  - Doty, Shayne, 1979-1984 (Box 2)
  - Doty, Shayne, with Winston-Salem Symphony, 1992 Feb. 8 (Box 2)
  - Duke Dance Club, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Duke Players, 1972-1975 (Box 2)
  - Duke University Calendar, 1957-1999, (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Duke University Museum of Art, 1969-1974 (Box 2)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce, 1965-1970 (Box 2)
  - Durham Children's Theatre Committee, 1968-1974 (Box 2)
  - Durham Savoyards, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Earls, Paul, 1969-1980 (Box 2)
  - 50th Anniversary Advisory Committee, 1974-1975, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Financial statement, 1972-1982, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Film policies, 1978-1982, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Fine Arts Committee of the University Planning Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Flentrop Organ Dedication, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Guest list--addresses up to 1984 (Box 3)
  - Hanks, Nancy, 1967-1983 (Box 3)
  - Hillyer, Raphael, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Hotel rates, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
  - House Counselors Luncheon, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Garrard, Mimi, 1969-1978 (Box 3)
  - Havinghurst, Karen, 1977-1981 (Box 3)
  - Institute of the Arts, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Jazz artists programs, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
  - Jazz on the Green, 1992-2000, (7 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jazz workshops, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Joe College Weekend, 1970-1972, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Kanengiser, William, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Ketterer, Steve, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Kimbrough, Steven, 1975-1976, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Kreps, Juanita, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Logo, undated (Box 3)
  - Lost Eden production, 1982, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Marsicano, Michael, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Mary Duke Biddle Music Building Dedication, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Mary Lou's Mass, 1979-1983 (Box 3)
  - Mary Lou Williams Jazz Festival, 1983-1998, (15 folders) (Box 3)
  - McCutcheon, John/Greensboro Justice Fund, 1989 Nov. 2 (Box 3)
  - Metropolitan Opera, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Miriam Makeba Scholarship, 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - Molière Festival, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Monthly Minder, Academic Year 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Murder in the Cathedral, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Murray-Louis Films, Dance as an Art Form, 1973-1976 (Box 3)
  - Museum Without Walls, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Department of Music, 1978-1981 (Box 3)
  - Music Conference, Tenth Annual, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - National Endowment for the Arts--grant application for solo recitalists, submitted July 28, 1980 (Box 3)
  - National Opera Company, 1973-1980 (Box 3)
  - New Performing Dance Company, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - North Carolina International Jazz Festival (Umbria), 1990 (Box 4)
  - North Carolina State Art Society, 1972-1978 (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Symphony, 1970-1979 (Box 4)
  - Noye's Fludde, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Nutcracker--co-sponsor agreements, 1996-2000 (Box 4)
  - Page Auditorium, 1934-1986, (16 folders)
    - Air conditioning, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
    - Category charts, 1965-1982 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1934-1965, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Facility configuration, 1941 and undated (Box 4)
    - Improvements and maintenance, 1956-1976, 1986, (4 folders) (Box 4)
      Contains blueprints.
    - Management, 1967-1984 (Box 4)
    - Outside organizational scheduling, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
    - Parking, 1968-1982 (Box 4)
    - Policies, 1962-1982 (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1968-1972 (Box 4)
    - Use forms, 1962-1964 (Box 4)
    - Use statistics, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
  - Page Box Office--annual fiscal reports, 1975-1978 (Box 4)
  - Performing Arts Endowment Fund, 1971-1976 (Box 4)
  - Perry, Francis, 1974-1976 (Box 4)
  - Piedmont Chamber Orchestra, 1973 (Box 4)
  - President's house--use of, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Price, Ruth Gordon Watts, 1976-1984 (Box 4)
  - Public relations, 1978-1983 (Box 4)
  - Quadrangle Pictures schedules, 1939, 1970-1987, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - "Raleigh's Dream" by Iain Hamilton: British-American Festival, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Report to the Trustees, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
  - Reports--arts at Duke, 1976-1979 and undated (Box 4)
  - Sanford, Terry, 1977-1979 (Box 4)
  - Seawright, James, 1966-1971 (Box 4)
  - Self-Study, 1976 (Box 4)
  - South Indian music, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Staff correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - Staff meetings, 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - Student Affairs Leadership Assistance Program (SALAP), 1984-1988 (Box 4)
  - SALAP, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - SALAP Review Committee, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Student employment, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Student organizations, 1967-1973, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Suderburg, Elizabeth, 1975-1977 (Box 5)
  - Summer Housing Program, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Symposium on Racism, 1972 (Box 5)
  - This Week at Duke, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Thompson, Clive, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Triangle Playhouse/Durham Star Playhouse, 1959-1962 (Box 5)
  - United Nations flags, 1964-1971 (Box 5)
  - University calendar--publication costs, 1970-1978 (Box 5)
  - University House, 1966-1968 (Box 5)
  - USA-USSR Track Meet and Summer Arts Festival, 1974, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Year End Report, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Zukofsky, Paul, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Duke University Molière Festival: Tercentenary Celebration, scrapbook, 1973 (Box 12)
- Chamber Arts Society, 1972-2002, (2 boxes)
  Primarily the records of fifteen seasons of chamber music concerts sponsored by the Society and Duke University from 1985-2000. Includes contracts, artist biographies, printed materials. amd approximately 200 black-and-white publicity photographs and 35mm slides of most performers. Records are arranged chronologically by season except for the first few folders of the series, which hold miscellaneous information about the history of the Society before its official connection with Duke was made permanent in 1975. Related materials in the Duke University Archives can also be found in the records and papers of Ernest W. Nelson, a professor of history who founded the Society in 1945.
  - History: budgets, correspondence, photographs, and printed materials, 1972-1996, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - History: brochures and programs, 1986-2002 (Box 5)
  - History: "Chamber Arts Society, 1945-1995: History of the Chamber Arts Society," Leland R. Phelps--Fiftieth Anniversary booklet, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Budgets and printed materials, 1979-1985, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1985-1986 Season
    - Emerson String Quartet, 1985 Nov. 9 (Box 5)
    - Aspen Wind Quintet, 1986 Jan. 18 (Box 5)
    - Beaux Arts Trio, 1986 Feb. 8 (Box 5)
    - Quartetto Beethoven di Roma, 1986 Mar. 1 (Box 5)
    - Masuko Ushioda, 1986 Mar. 1 (Box 5)
    - Musica da Camera Praga, 1986 Apr. 19 (Box 5)
    - Ridge String Quartet, 1986 Apr. 19 (Box 5)
  - 1986-1987 Season
    - Budget (Box 5)
    - Concert Season (Box 5)
    - Vermeer String Quartet, 1986 Sept. 27 (Box 5)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1986 Nov. 1 (Box 5)
    - Vienna Octet, 1987 Jan. 10 (Box 5)
    - Da Capo Chamber Players, 1987 Feb. 10 (Box 5)
    - Juilliard String Quartet, 1987 Mar. 7 (Box 5)
    - Ciesinski, Katherine, 1987 Mar. 21 (Box 5)
  - 1987-1988 Season
    - Budget (Box 5)
    - Concert Season (Box 5)
    - Mendelssohn String Quartet, 1987 Sept. 26 (Box 5)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1987 Oct. 31 (Box 5)
    - Pasquier String Quartet, 1987 Nov. 21 (Box 5)
    - Richard Stoltzman, 1988 Jan. 9 (Box 5)
    - Beaux Arts Trio, 1988 Feb. 27 (Box 5)
  - 1988-1989 Season
    - Program choices (Box 5)
    - Year-end reports, 1988-1994 (Box 5)
    - Guarneri String Quartet, 1988 Sept. 24 (Box 5)
    - Daniel String Quartet, 1988 Oct. 22 (Box 5)
    - Borodin Piano Trio, 1989 Jan. 14 (Box 5)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1989 Mar. 4 (Box 5)
    - American Chamber Players, 1989 Apr. 1 (Box 5)
  - 1989-1990 Season
    - Juilliard String Quartet, 1989 Sept. 23 (Box 5)
    - Aspen Wind Quintet, 1989 Nov. 3 (Box 5)
    - An Die Musik, 1989 Nov. 4 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1990 Jan. 20 (Box 6)
    - Bell, Joshua, 1990 Mar. 17 (Box 6)
    - Kronos Quartet, 1990 Mar. 29 (Box 6)
    - Dorian Wind Quartet, 1990 Apr. 7 (Box 6)
  - 1990-1991 Season
    - Brochure, 45th Season (Box 6)
    - Guarneri String Quartet, 1990 Sept. 22 (Box 6)
    - Beaux Arts Trio, 1990 Oct. 27 (Box 6)
    - Cremona Arts Trio, 1991 Jan. 19 (Box 6)
    - Franciscan String Quartet, 1991 Mar. 16 (Box 6)
    - Carol Wincenc and Jean Yves Thibaudet, 1991 Apr. 6, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1991-1992 Season
    - Season (Box 6)
    - Carter Brey and Christopher O'Riley, 1991 Sept. 21 (Box 6)
    - Borromeo Quartet, 1991 Oct. 26 (Box 6)
    - Quartetto Beethoven di Roma, 1991 Nov. 9 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1992 Jan. 18 (Box 6)
    - Cuarteto Latinoamericano (off-the-series special), 1992 Feb. 1 (Box 6)
    - American Chamber Players, 1992 Mar. 21 (Box 6)
    - Juilliard String Quartet, 1992 Apr. 11 (Box 6)
  - 1992-1993 Season
    - Season (Box 6)
    - Hexagon, 1992 Sept. 26 (Box 6)
    - Beaux Arts Trio, 1992 Nov. 7 (Box 6)
    - Ysaye Quartet, 1993 Jan. 30 (Box 6)
    - Uptown String Quartet (off-the-series special), 1993 Feb. 24 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1993 Feb. 27 (Box 6)
    - Emerson String Quartet, 1993 Apr. 3 (Box 6)
  - 1993-1994 Season
    - Brochure and miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Composers String Quartet with Daniel McKelway, 1993 Sept. 18 (Box 6)
    - Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center, 1993 Oct. 16 (Box 6)
    - Schill Quartet, 1993 Nov. 13 (Box 6)
    - Cremona Arts Trio with Kikuei Ikeda, 1993 Nov. 20 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1994 Jan. 15 (Box 6)
    - Hagen Quartett, 1994 Mar. 5 (Box 6)
  - 1994-1995 Season
    - Brochure and miscellaneous, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
    - Golub-Kaplan-Carr Trio, 1994 Sept. 17 (Box 6)
    - Takács Quartet, 1994 Oct. 1 (Box 6)
    - Emerson String Quartet, 1994 Nov. 19 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1995 Jan. 14 (Box 6)
    - Peabody Trio, 1995 Mar. 11 (Box 6)
    - Heinz Holliger, 1995 Mar. 25 (Box 6)
  - 1995-1996 Season
    - Booking (Box 6)
    - Brochures and subscribers list (Box 6)
    - Grants (Box 6)
    - Orion String Quartet, 1995 Sept. 30 (Box 6)
    - Borromeo String Quartet, 1995 Dec. 9 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1996 Feb. 10 (Box 6)
    - Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center, 1996 Mar. 9 (Box 6)
    - Ying Quartet, 1996 Mar. 30 (Box 6)
    - Juilliard String Quartet, 1996 Apr. 6 (Box 6)
  - 1996-1997 Season
    - Budget and brochures (Box 6)
    - Yayoi Toda, 1996 Sept. 28 (Box 6)
    - Walden Horn Trio, 1996 Oct. 12 (Box 6)
    - Emanuel Ax, 1996 Dec. 14 (Box 6)
    - Golub-Kaplan-Carr Trio, 1997 Jan. 18 (Box 6)
    - Emerson String Quartet, 1997 Mar. 22 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1997 Apr. 5 (Box 6)
  - Biddle-Nelson, Phelps, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Brochures, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979-1985, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1997-1998 Season
    - Year-end report, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
    - St. Petersburg String Quartet, 1997 Sept. 27 (Box 6)
    - Carter Brey and Christopher O'Riley, 1997 Nov. 8 (Box 6)
    - Paris Piano Trio, 1998 Jan. 17 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1998 Feb. 28 (Box 6)
    - Miami String Quartet, 1998 Mar. 21 (Box 6)
    - Vermeer String Quartet, 1998 Apr. 4 (Box 6)
  - 1998-1999 Season
    - Year-end report, 1998-1999 (Box 6)
    - The Guarneri String Quartet, 1998 Sept. 12 (Box 6)
    - The Eroica Trio, 1998 Oct. 10 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 1998 Oct. 31 (Box 6)
    - Emerson String Quartet, 1999 Jan. 23 (Box 6)
    - Ying Quartet, 1999 Mar. 13 (Box 6)
    - New York Chamber Soloists, 1999 Mar. 27 (Box 6)
  - 1999-2000 Season
    - Annual report, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
    - St. Petersburg String Quartet, 1999 Sept. 25 (Box 6)
    - Orion String Quartet, 1999 Dec. 11 (Box 6)
    - Emanuel Ax and Yoko Nozaki, 2000 Feb. 12 (Box 6)
    - Paris Piano Trio, 2000 Mar. 11 (Box 6)
    - Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center, 2000 Mar. 25 (Box 6)
    - Tokyo String Quartet, 2000 Apr. 22 (Box 6)
  - Michael Maas memorial contributions, 2001 (Box 6)
- Duke Artists Series, 1931-2002, (2 boxes)
  Primarily the records of several seasons of performances from the late-1980s and late-1990s, arranged in chronological order. Additionally, printed materials at the beginning of the series outline more than forty years' worth of concert seasons. Related material in the Duke University Archives can be found in the Duke Artists Series Records. Contains approximately 200 black-and-white publicity photographs and 35mm slides.
  - Anniversary brochures: 60th, 1930-1990; and 70th, 1930-2000 (Box 7)
  - Calendar notes and clippings, 1969-1970 season (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 7)
  - Photographs--miscellaneous publicity prints, 1985-1987 and undated (Box 7)
  - Season brochures, 1931-1932, 1952-1953, and 1964-2002, (3 folders) (Box 7)